Cummings School of Veterinary Medicine Records UA041
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Cummings School of Veterinary Medicine Records
1969 -- 2016
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Cummings School of Veterinary Medicine
UA041
25.3 Linear Feet 23 boxes and 1 oversize folder
43 Digital Object(s)
388 Megabytes
Arrangement
The collection is organized in eight series: Origins and planning; Office of the Dean, correspondence; Subject files; Programs and events; Executive faculty board minutes; Newspaper clippings and publicity materials; Masters theses; and Unprocessed accessions.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, publicity materials, reports, planning materials, minutes of the executive faculty board, masters theses, and subject files relating to the Cummings School of Veterinary Medicine.
Biographical / Historical
The School of Veterinary Medicine was established in 1978, opened in 1979, and graduated its first class in 1983. Established through the advocacy of President Jean Mayer, the school was unique in its affiliation to a health sciences complex rather than to a school of agriculture. The school is located on a 634 acre campus in Grafton, Massachusetts, site of a former state mental hospital. The school also shares facilities with the medical and dental schools on the downtown Boston campus, where vet students receive their first year of instruction in the basic sciences. Students at the veterinary school are exposed to care of all types of animals including food (cattle, sheep, swine, goat), fiber (sheep, llama), companion (dog, cat), and sporting (horse) animals. In addition, students are given the option of learning about care for wildlife through the wildlife medicine program. In addition to medicine, surgery, preventive medicine, and public health, the school also educates students about ethics, conservation medicine, and human-animal relationships.
Initial discussions on the establishment of a veterinary school were begun in the early 1970s as the absence of such a school in the New England region combined with a prediction of a nationwide deficit of veterinarians made the need apparent. After a variety of options were explored, including locating a school at the Otis Air Force base on Cape Cod, Tufts, under Jean Mayer's leadership, stepped forward to take the lead in the project. Richard B. Talbot, dean of the College of Veterinary Medicine at Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University was brought in as interim dean to oversee the startup of the school on a part-time basis. On April 29, 1978, the trustees voted to establish the school as part of Mayer's vision of an integrated "one medicine" program embracing the totality of medical, dental, veterinary, and nutrition education.
The school provides clinical facilities as part of the Tufts-New England Veterinary Medical Center, which includes the Foster Hospital for Small Animals, the Large Animal Hospital, the Cornelius Thibeault Equine Clinic, the Amelia Peabody Pavilion, the Issam Fares Equine Sports Medicine Program, the Harrington Oncology Program, and the Wildlife Clinic at Grafton, as well as the Marine Biological Laboratory at Woods Hole, and the Ambulatory Farm Clinic based at Woodstock, Connecticut.
The degree of Doctor of Veterinary Medicine (D.V.M.) is the primary degree offered by the school, though since 1995 the school also offers a Master of Science (M.S.) in Animals and Public Policy. The school features several signature programs which offer specialized perspectives on veterinary sciences, including Wildlife Medicine, Equine Sports Medicine, International Veterinary Medicine, Ethics and Values in Veterinary Medicine, and Biotechnology and Veterinary Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Administration and Governance -- Planning, evaluation, policies & procedures; Curriculum and Instruction -- Faculty; Administration and Governance -- Accreditation; Advancement; Facilities; Curriculum and Instruction
- Origins and planning, 1973 -- 1988; 1976 -- 1980; UA041.001; 2.4 Linear Feet; 1 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains reports and correspondence relating to the development of the School of Veterinary Medicine, including materials used in the feasibility study conducted by Arthur Anderson, Inc., and proposals for facilities in Grafton, Massachusetts. Most materials date from 1976 to 1980. Some of these materials appear to have been received from the office of the Vice President for Health Sciences, rather than from an office within the School of Veterinary Medicine itself. Other materials are of uncertain origin. In addition, reports such as the feasibility study and initial accreditation report, which pertain to the organization of the School and were found in early, relatively poorly organized materials as well as in later materials, are filed here. A copy of part of a Tufts University master's thesis (Factors in university decision Making: two studies) by Francine Trull and Bruce Cohen was originally part of the Russell Miller files on the School but was not retained; a copy is held in Tisch Library. These materials were received prior to 1997 and no clear record of origins and order is available.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Veterinary School, 1974 -- 1983; UA041.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Vet School Trustees, 1981 -- 1982; UA041.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary School budget projections, 1981 -- 1988; UA041.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary School capital project budget, 1 of 2, 1976 -- 1983; UA041.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary School capital project budget, 2 of 2, 1977 -- 1981; UA041.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary School budget, 1981 -- 1982; UA041.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Lab animal facilities, 1981 -- 1982; UA041.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Feasibility study - comments, draft 1, 1978; UA041.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    Book entitled Report of a study, costs of education in the health professions parts I & II, January 1974 (published by HEW, PHS, the Health Resources Administration, & the National Academy of Sciences) removed.
  - Final report on nontraditional sources of support for the Tufts University School of Veterinary Medicine, 1977; UA041.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Vet School - planning committee, 1976 -- 1979; UA041.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Otis AFB veterinary school study, 1974 -- 1976; UA041.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978; UA041.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1977 -- 1979; UA041.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Anderson & Co., letter with final report, 1978; UA041.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Anderson, Inc., - correspondence regarding feasibility study, 1976; UA041.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Anderson & Co., report distribution, 1978; UA041.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Anderson, Inc. - administration, 1977 -- 1978; UA041.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Anderson, Inc. - assumptions & methodology memos, 1978; UA041.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Anderson, Inc., library info., 1977 -- 1978; UA041.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Anderson, Inc. - misc. fact book materials, 1977 -- 1978; UA041.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Anderson, Inc. - memos regarding plans & planning, 1977 -- 1978; UA041.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Report of the committee to study the feasibilty of starting a school of veterinary medicine at Tufts University, 1976; UA041.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Committee to study the feasibility of establishing a veterinary school at Tufts University, progress reports, 1976 -- 1977; UA041.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - State hospital, Grafton - transfer of title, 1978; UA041.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Health sciences development task force (trustees of), 1978 -- 1979; UA041.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Health sciences development task force, 1978 -- 1979; UA041.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Financial projections for proposed school of veterinary medicine, 1978; UA041.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Accreditation manual, 1977; UA041.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Regional veterinary college, n.d., UA041.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - College of veterinary medicine for New England and New Jersey, a feasibilty study, 1973; UA041.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Feasibility of adding a small animal practice to the Grafton facility, 1984; UA041.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, construction grant, 1978; UA041.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary manpower, 1974 -- 1977; UA041.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Master plan concept study - Central New England campus, 1980; UA041.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Architectural drafts and notes, 1980; UA041.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Land grant university reports, correspondence, 1978; UA041.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Large animal hospital, architectural plans, n.d., UA041.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Health activities in Washington, 1978; UA041.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - Health Professions Educational Assistance Act, 1978; UA041.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - Accreditation and New Hampshire, 1979; UA041.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - Small animal hospital plans, 1984; UA041.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
    - Architect's rendering of the Small Animal Hospital, 1984; UA041.001.001.00041.00001; Warnecke Cannon, Inc. (Box 1)
      11 x 8
      Hospitals; Views; Drawings; School of Veterinary Medicine
  - Correspondence re: trustee, 1984; UA041.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary School, feasibility study, 1978; UA041.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
    Russell Miller file.
  - Veterinary School financial projections, 1978; UA041.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary School - academic highlights, 1984; UA041.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Mayer letter re: programs, 1977; UA041.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
    From the Russell Miller files on the Veterinary School.
  - Final feasibility study - financial statements, part 1 of 2, 1978; UA041.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Final feasibility study - financial statements, part 2 of 2, 1978; UA041.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Final feasibility study - basic sciences and O & M, part 1 of 2, 1978; UA041.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Final feasibility study - basic sciences and O&M, part 2 of 2, 1978; UA041.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Final feasibility study - Grafton & Angell, 1978; UA041.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Final feasibility study - capital, part 1 of 2, 1978; UA041.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Final feasibility study - capital, part 2 of 2, 1978; UA041.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Final feasibility study - othger operating revenue and expense, part 1 of 2, 1978; UA041.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Final feasibility study - other operating revenue and expense, part 2 of 2, 1978; UA041.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Program and predesign report (Warenecke / Ehrenkrantz / Desmond & Lord), 1979; UA041.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Proposed vehicle storage building plans, 1980; UA041.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Animal Hospital floor plan, 1981; UA041.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Veterinary School feasibility studies, 1976 -- 1977; UA041.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
- Office of the Dean, correspondence, 1979 -- 1998; UA041.002; 6.0 Linear Feet
  This series contains outgoing correspondence from the office of the Dean of the School of Veterinary Medicine. Includes the correspondence of Albert Jonas (dean from 1979 to 1981), W. Robert Cook (acting dean, 1981-82) and Franklin M. Loew (dean from 1982 to 1995). Materials date from 1979 to 1987.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  20 years from date of creation. Open for research.
  - Dean's office correspondence, 1980 -- 1981; UA041.002.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence, Jan-Mar., 1979; UA041.002.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence, Apr.-June, 1979; UA041.002.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence July - Aug., 1979; UA041.002.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence, Sept. - Oct., 1979; UA041.002.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence, Nov. - Dec., 1979; UA041.002.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence, Jan. - Apr., 1980; UA041.002.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence May - June, 1980; UA041.002.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence July - Sept., 1980; UA041.002.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence Sept. - Dec., 1980; UA041.002.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence Jan.- Mar, 1981; UA041.002.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence Apr. - June, 1981; UA041.002.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence July - Aug., 1981; UA041.002.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence Aug. - Oct., 1981; UA041.002.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence Nov. - Dec., 1981; UA041.002.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Dean's correspondence Jan. - Feb., 1982; UA041.002.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Feb/May [1 of 3], Apr.-May, 1982; UA041.002.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Feb/May [2 of 2], Mar. - Apr., 1982; UA041.002.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Feb/May [3 of 3], Mar., 1982; UA041.002.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, June / July, [1 of 2], June - July, 1982; UA041.002.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, June / July [2 of 2], June, 1982; UA041.002.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Aug./Oct. [1 of 3], Sept.-Oct., 1982; UA041.002.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Aug./Oct. [2 of 3], Aug. - Sept., 1982; UA041.002.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Aug. / Oct. [3 of 3], Aug., 1982; UA041.002.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Oct. / Dec. [1 of 2], Nov. -Dec., 1982; UA041.002.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Oct. / Dec. [2 of 2], Nov., 1982; UA041.002.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Jan./Mar. [1 of 2], Feb. - Mar., 1983; UA041.002.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Jan. / Mar. [2 of 2], Jan. - Feb., 1983; UA041.002.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Apr. / July [1 of 3], June-July, 1983; UA041.002.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Apr. / May [2 of 3], Apr. - June, 1983; UA041.002.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Apr./July [3 of 3], April, 1983; UA041.002.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Aug. / Dec. '83 [1 of 3], Oct. - Dec., 1983; UA041.002.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Aug. / Dec. '83 [2 of 3], Sept. - Oct., 1983; UA041.002.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Aug. / Dec. '83 [3 of 3], Aug. - Sept., 1983; UA041.002.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Jan. - Apr. '84 [1 of 3], Mar. - Apr., 1984; UA041.002.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Jan. -Apr. '82 [2 of 3], Feb. - Mar., 1984; UA041.002.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Jan. - Apr. '84 [3 of 3], Jan. - Feb., 1984; UA041.002.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office corresondence, Apr. - Aug. '84 [1 of 3], July - Aug., 1984; UA041.002.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, [2 of 3], June - July, 1984; UA041.002.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Apr. / Aug. '84 [ 3 of 3], Apr. - May, 1984; UA041.002.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Sept. '84 - Jan. '85 [1 of 3], Dec. 1984 - Jan., 1984 -- 1985; UA041.002.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Sept. '84 - Jan. '85 [3 of 3], Oct. - Dec., 1984; UA041.002.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Sept. '84 - Jan. '85 [3 of 3], Sept. - Oct., 1984; UA041.002.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Feb. - May '85 [1 of 2], Apr. - May, 1985; UA041.002.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Feb. / May '85 [2 of 2], Feb. - Apr., 1985; UA041.002.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, May - Oct. '85 [1 of 3], Aug. - Oct., 1985; UA041.002.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, May / Oct. '85 [2 of 3], June - Aug., 1985; UA041.002.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, May / Oct. '85 [3 of 3], May - June, 1985; UA041.002.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Oct. '85 / Feb. '86 [1 of 3], Jan. - Feb., 1986; UA041.002.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Oct. '85 / Feb. '86 [2 of 3], Nov. 1985 - Jan., 1985 -- 1986; UA041.002.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Oct. '85 / FEb. '86 [3 of 3], Oct. - Nov., 1985; UA041.002.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Mar. / June '86 [1 of 3], May - June, 1986; UA041.002.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Mar. / June 1986 [2 of 3], Mar. - May, UA041.002.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Mar. / June 1986 [3 of 3], Mar., UA041.002.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - Dean's office correspondence, June / Oct. '86 [part 1 of 3], Sept. - Oct., 1986; UA041.002.005.00001 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, June / Oct. '86 [part 2 of 3], Aug. - Sept., 1986; UA041.002.005.00002 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, June / Oct. '86 [part 3 of 3], June - Aug., 1986; UA041.002.005.00003 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Oct. '86 - Jan. '87 [part 1 of 2], Dec. 1986-Jan., 1986 -- 1987; UA041.002.005.00004 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Oct. '86- Jan. '87 [part 2 of 2], Oct. - Dec., 1986; UA041.002.005.00005 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Feb. - Apr. 1987 [part 1 of 3], Mar. - Apr., UA041.002.005.00006 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Feb. - Apr. '87 [part 2 of 3], Feb. - Mar., 1987; UA041.002.005.00007 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Feb. - Apr. '87 [part 3 of 3], Feb., 1987; UA041.002.005.00008 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Mary - July 1987 [part 1 of 2], June - July, UA041.002.005.00009 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, May - July '87, May - June, 1987; UA041.002.005.00010 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, July - Oct. '87 [part 1 of 2], Sept. - Oct., 1987; UA041.002.005.00011 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, July - Oct. '87 [part 2 of 2], Sept. - Oct., 1987; UA041.002.005.00012 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Nov. - Dec. '87 [part 1 of 2], Nov. - Dec., 1987; UA041.002.005.00013 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Dean's office correspondence, Nov. - Dec. '87 [part 2 of 2], Nov., 1987; UA041.002.005.00014 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence Binder December 5, 1988 - April 5, 1989 1 of 3, 1988 -- 1989; UA041.002.010.00001 (Box 10)
    20 years from date of creation.
  - Correspondence Binder December 5, 1988 - April 5, 1989 2 of 3, 1988 -- 1989; UA041.002.010.00002 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder December 5, 1988 - April 5, 1989 3 of 3, 1988 -- 1989; UA041.002.010.00003 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder December 4, 1989 - April 5, 1990 1 of 3, 1989 -- 1990; UA041.002.010.00004 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder December 4, 1989 - April 5, 1990 2 of 3, 1989 -- 1990; UA041.002.010.00005 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder December 4, 1989 - April 5, 1990 3 of 3, 1989 -- 1990; UA041.002.010.00006 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder April 9, 1990 - August 9, 1990 1 of 2, UA041.002.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder April 9, 1990 - August 9, 1990 2 of 2, UA041.002.010.00008 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder August 13, 1990 - December 27, 1990 1 of 2, UA041.002.010.00009 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder August 13, 1990 - December 27, 1990 2 of 2, UA041.002.010.00010 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder January 2, 1991 - June 26, 1991 1 of 3, UA041.002.010.00011 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder January 2, 1991 - June 26, 1991 2 of 3, UA041.002.010.00012 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder January 2, 1991 - June 26, 1991 3 of 3, UA041.002.010.00013 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1991 - December 27, 1991 1 of 2, UA041.002.010.00014 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1991 - December 27, 1991 2 of 2, UA041.002.010.00015 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder January 1992 - June 30, 1992 1 of 3, UA041.002.010.00016 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder January 1992 - June 30, 1992 2 of 3, UA041.002.010.00017 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder January 1992 - June 30, 1992 3 of 3, UA041.002.010.00018 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1992 - December 1992 1 of 2, UA041.002.011.00001 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1992 - December 1992 2 of 2, UA041.002.011.00002 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder January 1993 - June 30, 1993 1 of 3, UA041.002.011.00003 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder January 1993 - June 30, 1993 2 of 3, UA041.002.011.00004 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder January 1993 - June 30, 1993 3 of 3, UA041.002.011.00005 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1, 1993 - December 29, 1993 1 of 3, UA041.002.011.00006 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1, 1993 - December 29, 1993 2 of 3, UA041.002.011.00007 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1, 1993 - December 29, 1993 3 of 3, UA041.002.011.00008 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder January 1, 1994 - June 30, 1994 1 of 2, UA041.002.011.00009 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder January 1, 1994 - June 30, 1994 2 of 2, UA041.002.011.00010 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1, 1994 - December 31, 1994 1 of 2, UA041.002.011.00011 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder July 1, 1994 - December 31, 1994 2 of 2, UA041.002.011.00012 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder January 3, 1995 - December 31, 1995 1 of 3, UA041.002.011.00013 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder January 3, 1995 - December 31, 1995 2 of 3, UA041.002.011.00014 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder January 3, 1995 - December 31, 1995 3 of 3, UA041.002.011.00015 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder Chronological File, 1996; UA041.002.011.00016 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder Chronological File Jan - June, 1997; UA041.002.011.00017 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder July - Dec, 1997; UA041.002.011.00018 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder Jan - June, 1998; UA041.002.011.00019 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence Binder July - December, 1998; UA041.002.011.00020 (Box 11)
- Subject files, 1969 -- 1986; 1978 -- 1984; UA041.003; 3.6 Linear Feet
  This series contains files primarily from the office of the Dean of the School of Veterinary Medicine and relate to topics such as legislation, funding, and curriculum. While most material relating to the development and planning of the School are contained in series I, Origins and planning, this series also includes some information on the development of the school in the mid- and late-1970s. A copy of the report to the Visiting Committee (1981) was originally included in this collection but was removed as it is duplicated in Jean Mayer's presidential papers (Subject files, Veterinary School - visiting committees, 3-year plan). Some files are from the office of Irwin Leav, Associate Dean for Academic Affairs, and some materials received as part of Dean Albert Jonas' files appear to have been originally in the files of Tom Murnane, Special Assistant to the President.
  This series is arranged as found within each dean's administration with files from the earliest deans coming first in sequence. Dean Jonas' files run from box 5, folder 15 through box 7, folder 4 (including all of box 6); Assoc. Dean Leav's files are in box 6 (folders 6-35); and Dean Loew's files are contained in box 7, folders 36-44.
  - 1977, UA041.003.005.00015 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Resources: fundraising, 1978 -- 1979; UA041.003.005.00016 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Vermont, 1978; UA041.003.005.00017 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Westborough, 1978; UA041.003.005.00018 (Box UA041 Shared 1)
  - Organization charts, 1978; UA041.003.005.00019 (Box UA041 Shared 1)